Finding Aid for the Photograph Album Collection LSC.0094
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Architectural views of Los Angeles and vicinity., circa 1920s; no.201; (Photograph album with 50 images)
  Interior and exterior views of buildings interleaved with identification of the architects and building materials.
- Geology of Southern California., circa 1900-06; no.202; (5 items, Photograph albums)
  Photographed by or collected by Johnson.
  These albums date from the time he worked with USGS, with some of the photographs by other USGS photographs. One album is devoted entirely to the San Francisco earthquake of 1906. A register of the collection is in the Collections files.
  Johnson worked for the U.S. Geological Survey until he graduated from Stanford in 1906. Thereafter, he was consultant to various oil companies and lived in the Santa Monica area. His papers are at the University of Wyoming.
- Ansichten and Kunstwerke von Lubeck., circa 1900; no.203; (Photograph album with 10 cabinet photographs)
  The Dance of Death mural in the church at Lubeck encased in a brown cloth portfolio. Included are a photograph of the interior and one of the exterior of the church.
  Boxed with 94/202 box 3.
- Macpherson's Vatican Sculptures. Rome., circa 1860s; no.204; (Photograph album with 127 albumen prints)
  Mounted on the first leaf is a list, printed by Emily Faithfull, of the images with instructions for ordering them.
- Southern California Snapshot Album., circa 1920; no.205; (176 images)
  Views in Los Angeles and the nearby beaches.
- Australia (Sydney)., circa 1895; no.206; (Photograph album with 30 albumen prints)
  Many identified in the plate.
- Vistas de La Plata: desde su fundacion noiembre 1882 hasta junio 1884: 1. edicion. Buenos Aires (Argentina)., circa 1884; no.*207; (Photograph album with 39 albumen prints)
  Photographs by Tomas Bradley recording the founding of La Plata, capital of the Province of Buenos Aires. Introduction in Spanish, English, French and Italian.
- Italian albums., no.**208; (2 boxes, unprocessed)
- Theater albums., no.*209; (Unprocessed)
- Recuerdo del XXXII Congreso Eucaristico Internacional. Buenos Aires., 10-14 October 1934; no.210
  Aspects of the International Eucharistic Congress celebrated in Buenos Aires. Portraits of clergy members, military and government officials, crowds of religious followers, and views of the event.
- Album de photographias do Estado de Sao Paulo., 1892; no.211
  Panoramic views of the city, street scenes, business areas, fagades of public buildings, churches, parks, harbors, construction of stone paved streets, fountains, markets, a military parade, railroad stations, and animals.
  Identified photographer: Ganslay.
- Brazil., no.**212; (Photograph album, unprocessed)
  List included.
- Album do Rio de Janeiro., no.213; (14 images)
  Views of Rio de Janeiro's natural landscapes, public buildings, and street scenes. An impressionistic treatment with attention to light, artistic composition, and the use of sepia and gold toning.
- Hermosillo, Mexico, and the Carrizal hacienda., circa 1910-15; no.214; (Photograph album with 39 images)
  Panoramic views of Hermosillo, orange groves, buildings (Coliseum, Arcadia Hotel, Bank of Sonora, public market etc.), street scenes, water carriers, thrashing beans, water pumping, animals and natural landscapes.
- Travels of a tramp (Panama, Costa Rica and Mexico)., no.215; (Photograph album with 31 images)
  Views of towns from the sea; street and sidewalk scenes; buildings; railroad tracks in Mexico, Costa Rica, Nicaragua and Panama, including the American Quarter in the Canal Zone.
- Shoe factory in Brazil., no.216; (Photograph album, unprocessed)
  Boxed with **94/212.
- Album do Rio de Janeiro., circa 1930s; no.217; (2 vol. of 3 vol. set [1-2], unprocessed)
- Recuerdos del Paraguay. The Paraguayan war., 1869-70; no.218; (Photograph album with 23 images)
  Portraits of troops, cities after war, women and children as prisoners-of-war, churches, construction of a palace, railroad stations, rural areas, and a photo-reproduction of an etched boat image.
  Photographs by Forni.
- Cuban urban and rural scenes., circa 1880; no.219; (Photograph album with 30 images)
  Views of sugar plantations, street scenes, bull fights, farmhouses, oxcarts on cobbled streets, and portraits.
- Vistas y costumbres de la Republica Argentina., no.220; (58 images)
  A family photograph album with views of a cattle ranch, humorous group portraits of men and women probably related to the compiler of the album; animals, horsemen, and hounds. Possibly compiled by Cotton.
  Identified photographer: Samuel Boote.
- Brazil., no.221; (Photograph album, unprocessed)
  Boxed with 94/217.
- Los Angeles Times Oriental excursion party., no.222; (Unprocessed)
  Boxed with **94/223.
- Japan., no.**223; (Photograph album, unprocessed)
  Gift of Albert Boni, 1973 (Boni backlog no.85222).
- Japan., no.*224; (Photograph album with wood lacquer case and burnished gold lake scene, unprocessed)
- Japan., no.*225; (Photograph album with wood lacquer case, rickshaw on one side, butterfly and flowers on other, unprocessed)
- Sugar factory 'Tjepper'., no.226; (54 original photographs)
  With descriptions in Dutch. Offered to the Director of the Factory, R.H. Erdman, covering his period (1904-1929).
- Indonesia - Northern Celebes., circa 1925; no.**227; (Photograph album with 135 original photographs mounted on 17 stiff leaves)
  Boxed with 94/226.
- Views of Egypt., no.*228; (Unprocessed)
- African gold mine album., no.*229; (Photograph album, unprocessed)
  Notes in album, including ephemera.
  Boxed with *94/228.
- Turkish album., 1891; no.*230; (Photograph album, unprocessed)
- Roma., no.*231; (Unprocessed)
- Travel album., no.*232; (With over 160 photographs, unprocessed)
  Signed 'Flora Moore Reed'.
  Boxed with *94/231.
- Photographs connected with Afghanistan collection. The Wattle Grove Press., no.233; (Unprocessed)
- Trip to England and France by Eli and Esther --- of Los Angeles., December 1923-25; no.*234; (Unprocessed)
- Los Angeles, etc., no.#235; (Photograph album, unprocessed)
  Bound with *94/234.
- Burnett family photograph album., no.236; (Photograph album, unprocessed)
- Fishmongers's Company: the Barge., no.237; (Unprocessed)
- Snapshot albums., 1907/08; May-July 1926; 1929-36; no.238; (3 vol., unprocessed)
  Boxed with 94/237.
- Osteopathy Class. Los Angeles., circa 1914; no.239; (Photograph album, unprocessed)
- New Zealand album of a mail carrier., no.240; (Photograph Album, unprocessed)
- Collection of workshop photographs., no.*241; (Unprocessed)
  (See Boni folder)
  Gift of Albert Boni, 1973.
- Collection of photographs, including Broomland House., no.*242; (Unprocessed)
- Ruins of Paris and environs., circa 1870; no.*243; (51 photographs)
  Possibly during time of Paris Commune.
- Life in Europe., 1904-51; no.*244; (1 item)
- California criminals sentenced to death by hanging., 1892-1903; no.245; (1 photograph album)
- Criminal photograph album., 1903-04; no.246
  Boxed with 94/245.
- Recuerdo de Montevideo por Bate y Ca. Montevideo[?]: Bate y Ca., 1880s[?]; no.247
- Peña Chica, the Atacama Desert, and nitrate exploitation in Chile., circa 1912; no.248; (Photograph album with 87 images)
  Views of the nitrate industry in Chile: warehouses, transportation, processing plants and workers. Group portraits of businessmen, and portraits of a young man in various settings, including relatives(?) and pets.
- Various Mexican locations and scenes., circa 1890-1910; no.249; (Photograph album with 161 images)
  Panoramic views of Mexican cities, rural areas, natural wonders, monuments, interior view of Chapultepec Castle, bullfighting, floating garden views, flower and fruit series, and crafts.
  Identified photographers: C.B. Waite, Scott, Carmichael, Cox, and Briquet.
- Album grafico de las visitas oficiales del gobernador constitucional del Estado de Mexico C. Carlos Riva Palacio., 1926; no.250; (398 images)
  Palacio's official visits to cities and towns of the state of Mexico as governor. Many group portraits of the governor and supporters at political events.
  Photographs by Laborde.
- Brazil - Various rural and urban scenes., circa 1885-1906; no.251; (Photograph album with 138 images)
  Panoramic views of Rio de Janeiro, Sao Paulo, Pernambuco, Bahia, Porto Alegre and other cities, rural areas and landscapes, portraits of Bahian types and Indians, and Sao Paulo's railroad tracks and viaducts.
- Military - World War 1., no.252; (Photograph album with 64 images)
  Taken in France and Belgium.
- Banana trade in Honduras., circa 1900; no.253; (Photograph album with 12 images)
  Panoramic views of various towns related to the banana trade, ox carts transporting bananas, sea shore storage, banana ship, and group portraits of men and soldiers.
- Scenic views along the Mexican National Railroad tracks., circa 1905; no.254; (Photograph album with 238 images)
  Views of monuments, historical sites, and street scenes of cities and countryside, including San Antonio, Texas.
- Mexican generals, clergy members, women and children who may be related to General Paz Alvarez family., circa 1880-1890; no.256; (Photograph album with 98 carte de visite portraits)
- Mexican centennial events and inauguration of President Alvaro Obregon., 1921; no.257; (Photograph album with 188 images)
  Portraits of President Alvaro Obregon and members of his cabinet, views of events during the centennial celebration, the military parade, traditional dances, cultural and political activities, and the people's participation.
  Identified photographer: Sosa y Diaz.
- Brazil. Rio de Janeiro., circa 1915; no.258; (2 colored panoramic photogravures)
- Various scenes of Rio de Janeiro. Rio de Janeiro: Maison Chic., 1910s; no.259; (69 images)
  Views of Rio de Janeiro, including public buildings, main avenues, street scenes with electric cars and mule carts, and views from the Pao D'Assucar cable car.
- Vues de Rio de Janeiro, Bresil (Rio de Janeiro: Le Musso & Cia., 1900s[?]; no.260; (34 images)
  Portrait of President Nilo Pecanha and cabinet members, views of government buildings, major avenues and streets, plazas, panoramic view of the city towards the ocean, the botanical garden and the Tijuca waterfall.
- Brazil, including Sao Paulo, Santos, Guaruja., circa 1925; no.261; (Photograph album with 35 images)
  Panoramic views of Santos, Sao Paulo, monuments, public cultural buildings, tea harvesting, orange and coffee plantations, and aspects of coffee production.
- Mexico., circa 1900; no.262; (48 images)
  Including urban and rural views of Guadalajara, Mexico City and other locations.
  Views of rural scenes (women washing clothes, water carriers); street scenes, portraits, religious buildings, Chapultepec Castle, statues, missions and diverse views of towns.
- Ferrez, Marc. Avenida Central., 8 de Marco de 1903, 15 de Novembro; no.263; (184 plates)
  [Views of] Rio de Janeiro.
- Photograph album., no.264
- Consejo Nacional de Educacion (Argentina). Vistas de escuelas comunes., 1889; no.265; (41 images)
  Views of public schools' fagades and interiors, portraits of school children in classrooms and children from military school.
- Boote, Samuel, and others., no.266; (34 images)
  19th century photographs of Argentina and Chile, including Tierra del Fuego.
- Vistas del camino de La Oroya a la montana de Chanchamayo: photograph album of Peru (Lima y Callao: Colville & Cia, s.a.)., no.267
- Guanajuato en el ano de mil novecientos treinta y siete. Mexico., 1941; no.268
- Photo album of Banana industry in Costa Rica., 1900s[?]; no.269
- S. Charles Lee's Los Angeles Theater., no.270; (Photograph album with 20 images)
  Views of the interior of the theater, including the auditorium, lounges, foyer, children's playroom and details of furniture and interior decoration.
- Cananea, Sonora, Mexico, and Ray, Arizona., circa 1909; no.271; (Photograph album with 60 images)
  Views of Cananea, the mines, mass meetings, railroads, baseball team and many informal family pictures. Also one blueprint of Ray, Arizona, taken before the fire of 1912.
- Whittier and Southern California., 1900-03; no.272; (Photograph album)
  Many views of Whittier and C.W. Leffingwell's ranch, including buildings, relatives and friends.
  Also, views of Santa Monica, Mount Lowe, Catalina, Long Beach, La Fiesta de Las Flores, 1902 Tournament of Roses, Kern County, Bakersfield, San Bernardino, Riverside, Redondo Beach and Los Angeles.
- California views., circa 1910s; no.273; (Photograph album with 68 images including 5 panoramic views)
  Views include the Pala Reservation, the San Diego Flume, the San Luis Rey Valley, and general views of irrigation and redwood trees.
- United States Navy Midshipmen., 1860s; no.274; (Photograph album with 23 carte-de-visite images)
- Family photograph album., circa 1870s-1920s; no.275
  Many views of the Hagan family and their home, together with views of the Los Angeles area, including the Elks parades of the 1890s, and Pasadena.
  Also there are views of Northfield, Minnesota, Colorado, Honolulu, Salt Lake City and Saltair on the Great Salt Lake.
- Album de Blumenau., circa 1916; no.276; (12 images)
  The town of Blumenau in Brazil, including a panorama of the town, and views of the river, streets, buildings, churches and railway station.
- Sao Paulo Antigo., 1860; no.277; (59 images)
  Views of city streets, churches, hotels, and theaters. Also views of the outskirts of the city and of country houses round Sao Paulo. Most views ca 1860, with one from 1887.
- Cuba., 1897-1899; no.278; (Photograph album)
  Views of the Cuban countryside, Santiago and its harbor, Havana and its harbor, including the wreck of the USS Maine, and theaters, plazas, buildings, and the cathedral in Havana.
- Palestine., circa 1867-1871; no.279; (Photograph album with 84 albumen prints)
  Views of the towns and cities and countryside of Palestine. Many views of the gates, walls and streets of Jerusalem.
  Also views of Bethlehem, Nazareth, Galilee and Capernum.
- Family., circa 1880s; no.280; (Photograph album with 86 images)
  [Includes] 2 hand-colored of an unidentified American family.
  Gift of George W. Schuyler.
- Unidentified family (American)., circa 1880s; no.280; (Photograph album with 86 images, 2 hand-colored, fine leather binding with metalwork decoration on front)
  Gift of Mr. George W. Schuyler.
- Europe., n.d.; no.281; (Photograph album with 347 images, sizes vary from 3.5 × 2.25" to 11 × 8.5")
  Views of the south of England, including the Isle of Wight, Scotland, Wales and Ireland.
  Also, views of France,Belgium, Holland, Germany, Switzerland and Italy.
- Old Charterhouse., circa 1880s[?]; no.282; (11.5 × 9" Photograph album with 16 pictures)
  The old Charter House hospital founded by Thomas Sutton for the poor.
- The Communards., 1871; no.283; (9 × 6.5" Photograph album with 93 pictures)
  Men and women involved in the French commune. Everyone is named, and the fate of many of them is also listed.
- Antiquities of France and Italy., no.284; (6 vol. of photograph albums, photographs mounted on linen and of various sizes)
  vol.1) France - Churches.
  vol.2) France - Buildings.
  vol.3) France - Interiors.
  vol.4) France - Musee de Cluny.
  vol.5) Italy - Museums and landscapes.
  vol.6) France - Chateaux.
- Union Army field grade officers., no.285-288; (4 carte-de-visite photograph albums containing 189 portraits)
  Including Grant, Rosecrans, Sherman, etc. Most were published by E. & H.T. Anthony.
  Albums are part of group collected by Albert Boni.
- Australian Theatrical company on tour., 1907-1908; no.289; (Photograph album with 144 images, 6 × 8.5")
  Views of Australia (Melbourne, Adelaide, Perth, Kalgoorlie), Sri Lanka (Colombo), Egypt (Port Said and the Suez Canal), Italy (Pompeii and Naples), France (Marseilles), England (Brighton, Chatham, Rochester, Ascot, Epsom, Newton Abbott, Portsmouth, Southampton), Ireland (Dublin, Blarney, Clonakilty, Miltown), and Scotland.
- Mexico., circa 1940-1950; no.290; (Photograph album with 150 images, all approximately 16.5 × 13 cm.)
  Views primarily of the floating gardens of Xochimilco outside Mexico City, including its markets, boats, and restaurants.
  There are also views of a small country bull ring, bulls being raised for the ring, and an hacienda.
  From the estate of Urie McCleary.
- Portraits., n.d.; no.291; (Carte-de-visite photograph album with 27 images)
  A few of the identified notables.
  Collected by Albert Boni.
- Soldiers and civilians., no.292; (Carte-de-visite photograph album with 39 portraits)
  Published by E. & H.T. Anthony.
- The Two Orphans cast., no.293; (Carte-de-visite photograph album with 21 portraits)
  Issued as a souvenir with title of play and name of theatre on binding.
- Military and civilians., no.294; (Carte-de-visite photograph album with 43 portraits)
- Italy., no.295; (22 albumen prints, size either approximately 9.5 × 7" or 13.5 × 10", Mounted 20.75 × 14")
  Views include the Bay of Naples, Pompeii, St. Peter's Square in Rome, Florence and various statuary.
- London., circa 1930; no.296; (Photograph album with 43 images, all approximately 30 × 26 cm.)
  Aerial views of the River Thames, principal bridges over the river, important landmarks along the river and central London.
  Also, views of Stepney in East London, including the brewery and several streets.
- Buenos Aires., circa 1880s; no.297; (12.5 × 10" Photograph album with 61 images, all approximately 7 × 8.5")
  Views in and around Buenos Aires, including the port, casa del gobierno, customs house, Palermo, the Recoleta, La Boca, Corrales, stations and churches.
  Gift of Olga Mingo Hoffman.
- Trip to Europe., 1896; no.298; (11 × 16" Photograph album with 112 images, all 3 × 4")
  Photographs taken by teenage son of Dr. and Mrs. Bridge[?].
  Includes views on board the S.S. St. Louis, and of France, Switzerland, Italy and Germany.
- Japan., early 1900s; no.299; (11 × 14" Photograph album with 22 colored images, 8 × 10")
  Includes views of the Japanese countryside agricultural workers, sumo wrestling tournament, Kyoto and Yokohama.
- Pantages Theater., 1930; no.300; (8.25 × 11.2" Photograph album with 44 images, 8 × 10")
  Views at time of theater's opening, of the ticket office, entrance, foyer, furniture, auditorium, lounges, powder rooms and exterior with searchlights.
- Peru., circa 1900s; no.301; (3 vol. of 7.5 × 10" Photograph albums with 108 images, 3.5 × 4.5-5.5")
  Views include Lima, Ancon, Chorillos, along the line of the Central railway from Lima to La Oroya and the Cerro de Pasco Railway from La Oroya to Cerro de Pasco, and towns and countryside in Pasco and Huanuco departments.
  Glage appears to have worked at the smelter at La Fundicion.
- Southern California family., circa 1908-1922; no.302; (7.25 × 11.25" Photograph album with 181 images)
  Views include Point Fermin, Long Beach, Mojave Desert, Lancaster, Pasadena, Ocean Park, Venice, Antelope Valley, Balboa Beach, Laguna Beach, Torrey Pines, the 1920 Rose parade, and various family beach scenes.
- Miscellany., circa 1940s; no.303; (Photograph album with 175 images, 11 × 16")
  Views include the early weeks of the Manzanar War Relocation Center, Monterey Presidio, Seattle, Inglewood, California, army training camp, tanks, various parts of California, and family snapshots.
  Also includes Durbin's 1946 commission into the U.S. Army Corps.
- Miscellany., circa 1946-1954; no.304; (Photograph album with 19 images, 11.5 × 15.25")
  Includes views of the Southwest Junior Rifle Club, automobile racing in the Los Angeles area, and shooting and automobile racing ephemera.
- South American mining., 1924-1931; no.305; (11 × 16" Photograph album with 613 photographs, 7 prints, and 3 maps on 69 leaves - majority of images 3.5 × 5.5")
  Almost all images are snapshots taken by owner of album, and all are clearly labeled. Views are of both various kinds of mining as well as of cities and countryside and are especially strong on Chile (179 photographs), Guianas (139 photographs) and Peru (93 photographs).
  Also includes pictures of Argentina, Brazil, Bolivia, Uruguay, Panama, Trinidad, U.S. Virgin Islands and New York.
- Arthur C. Bilicke Family., 1903-1913; no.306; (11.25 × 15.75" Photograph album with 70 images)
  Views include Bilicke mansion site in South Pasadena before construction, construction of building, house and estate after completion, many with Bilicke's children featured, and snapshots of Bilicke children, many in fancy dress at "Camp Harvard."
- Eli Harper Family., 1922-1940; no.307; (7.25 × 11.5" Photograph album with 259 images on 100pp., photos range in size from 2 × 2.5" to 4 × 6")
  Includes many family snapshots, as well as views of Brawley, Indio, Holtville, Cuyamarca, the San Diego zoo, and many rural locations around San Diego and Imperial counties.
- Rose Lane., 1915-1921; no.308; (7 × 11.25" Photograph album with 289 images on 100pp., photographs approximately 2.5 × 3.5")
  Snapshots of Rose Lane, her friends, sister and family[?]. Taken in various locations in Virginia, Kentucky, Ohio and Tennessee.
  Also, views of Washington, D.C. from a trip in 1921.
- Africa's Legacy: Photographs in Brazil and Peru., 1999; no.309; (11.25 × 9.5" Photograph album with 83 images, all 8 × 10")
  43 images from Peru and 40 images from Brazil, each with own title page and preface. The pictures of Peru were taken in Chincha and Lima between 1985 and 1986, and the pictures of Brazil were taken in the Northeast in 1995 and 1996.
  Pictures are of everyday life of the poor.
- Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce Excursion to the Islands of Hawaii., 1907; no.310; (10.25 × 12.75" Photograph album with 46 images on 46pp.)
  Includes views of group leaving San Pedro, en route to Hawaii, at various locations around the islands, and leaving the islands.
- Alaska., circa 1902-1906; no.311; (10.25 × 13.5" Photograph album with 101 images)
  Includes views of Nome and St. Michael, as well as scenes from everyday life in and around western Alaska. Also, views of mines and mining, railroads, ships, the seashore, eskimos[?], and dogs.
- Alt-Augsburg., circa 1900s; no.312; (12.75 × 9.75" Photograph album with 10 images)
  Views of buildings, trees and river in Augsburg.
- U.S. Naval School (Hunter College)., no.313; (10.25 × 11.5" Photograph album with 88 images, 4 × 5")
  Sequence of photographs shows WAVES (Women Accepted for Voluntary Emergency Service) from visiting recruiting office, through induction, training, social life, and going on parade, to passing out of training college.
- Vitoria, in the state of Espirito Santo, Brazil., 1908-1911; no.314; (8.75 × 12.25" Photograph album with 79 images)
  Views of the city. Many pairs of views comparing scenes before and after improvements have been made. Most photographs captioned. Some hand-painted decoration.
  (Severe foxing throughout)
- Mexico., circa 1890s; no.315; (10 × 9.25" Photograph album with 49 images)
  21 photographs signed by Abel Briquet.
  Views include several city views of Mexico City, Puebla, Zacatecas, Tacubaya and other cities, as well as many of the countryside, showing peasants at work and at their homes.
  Also, 9 photos of pre-colonial statuary.
- Colombia and Norway., 1920-1930s[?]; no.316; (8.5 × 10.5" Photograph album with 177 photographs and 2 postcards)
  110 views of Colombia, especially of Baranquilla, the Magdalena River and the emerald mines at Chivor.
  Also, 46 views of Norway, including Stavanger and Sand; rural England, Martinique and St. Tropez, France.
  With "Lecture on South America" by an anonymous author on his trip to Colombia and his experiences in the emerald mines, February 1, 1927 (15pp. typescript).
- Photograph album Mexico, 1883-1900; no.320
- Photograph album of Rio de Janeiro, 1960s; no.321
  Other Finding Aids